(upbeat music)
- So here's a story from my own life
about changing the narrative
that I was telling myself
about stress, changing
the story I was telling
myself about stress,
like finding a new context
in which to hold a stressor,
and how when I did that, it
changed my relationship to that
which was stressing me out.
And it changed my relationship so much,
that I was able then to do that thing
which was stressing me
out more effectively
and actually become
quite good at that thing.
And so when I was in high
school, I joined the debate team.
And here's a picture of myself
in high school with a friend.
And part of being on the debate team is
we had to give speeches.
And the first time I ever
had to give a speech,
I was so nervous
that when they called my
name, I didn't get up.
I just continued to sit in
my chair in the audience
and then they called my name again,
and I still didn't get
up and sweat started
just to run down my body.
I could feel the sweat
running down my body.
I thought: Wow, I am so freaked out.
I'm so nervous. I'm so stressed.
And then they called my name a third time,
and I was so nervous
about getting up and giving a
speech, so stressed about it,
I still didn't get up.
And then they called my
name a fourth and final time
and they said, this is your last chance.
If you don't get up now,
you're forfeiting your,
you know, your right to give a speech
and to be entered in the contest;
you won't be able to give a speech.
And so I finally got up,
and I gave a speech and
it was mediocre at best.
And then afterwards I
talked to my speech coach,
and he said: Hey, don't try to get rid
of the butterflies, try to
get them to fly in formation.
Try to get them to fly in formation.
And so he gave me a new
story, a new narrative,
a new context in which
I could hold this thing
which was stressing me out,
getting up and giving a speech
in front of people, and
having that new story,
I was then able to relax around,
like, being nervous and,
oh yeah, I'm nervous.
I'm not trying to get
rid of the nervousness.
Let me just try to get those butterflies
to fly in formation.
Let me try to use all that energy that's
within me to accomplish this
thing that I want to do;
be able to talk in front of people,
be able to give a speech,
be able to be on the debate team, right?
Let me learn how to do that effectively.
And when I'm nervous,
let me just use that energy to deliver
a more energetic performance
with more enthusiasm, right?
So let me use that energy.
And so I reframed. I reframed.
In psychology, this is called reframing.
I reframed my perspective
on that stressor.
And in so doing, I changed my relationship
with that stressor, and
I was able to perform
at a more effective and optimal level,
and I actually became
quite good at debate,
and then I went on to college
and university and, you know,
and now I'm a professor,
and I give talks to public audiences,
to audiences all the time,
and I teach and do public
speaking as my profession.
And so that's just an
example to illustrate
how when we change our story,
our narrative that we're telling ourselves
about stress or something
that's stressing us out,
if we change the context in
which we're holding stress,
it changes our relationship
with stress or with that stressor.
It changes our relationship
and allows us to perform
at a more effective and optimal level.
And so this is all just to
illustrate the key takeaway
from the course that the
mind is incredibly powerful
and that the stories we
tell ourselves about stress,
influence how we respond
and react to stress.
In the next video,
we're gonna take a look at
a couple of course details.
See you in the next video.
(upbeat music)