(gentle music)
- All right, I wanna
give you a few details
about this course.
And the first thing I wanna
share with you is how we learn.
And this is me with one
of the greatest teachers
in my life, my mom,
and this course, I'll say this
right here at the beginning,
this course is going to be
drawing upon personal
experiences from my own life.
And the reason it's gonna
draw upon personal experiences
from my own life, and you
can see right here, personal,
is that we learn in three primary areas.
We learn one, from theory,
and then we also learn from experience.
And then we also learn from example,
which is the experience of others.
And so, theory, experience and example
are like the three categories,
three main areas we learn.
And just to illustrate
this with an example,
if you were gonna learn
how to play basketball,
first somebody would tell you,
"Look, this is how you play basketball."
They'd give you the theory, right?
And then you'd go out on
the court and you'd try.
You'd get experience,
you'd actually try it
and you'd learn from trying to dribble,
trying to shoot the ball.
So you'd learn from theory,
you'd learn from experience.
And then you'd also learn from example,
like you'd see somebody
else do an amazing move
and you'd be like, "Oh, I
want to do that move, too."
And then you could go practice that move
and start to own that move yourself.
So, we learn from the
experiences of others.
And because we learn in these
three ways, in this course,
you'll be given theory.
You'll also be given a chance to apply
some of that theory with exercises
so you'll be able to
learn through experience.
And then I'm also gonna share
some examples from my own life.
So, it'll be personal in that way.
This course will be personal.
There'll be pictures from my own life
and that will allow you to
learn from my own experience,
from the examples of others.
So, just letting you
know why there's so many
pictures of me in the course sometimes.
I'm just trying to make
it a personable course
where you learn from my experiences,
and then also just when
you know your teacher,
also, data shows that you
learn more effectively
when you feel a connection
with your teacher.
So that's also why I'm keeping things
a little bit personal in the course.
To manage some expectations,
I'm down in the basement of
our home and we've got two dogs
and here are pictures of those
dogs, and they're upstairs.
And sometimes if like the
postman or delivery person comes,
they'll bark.
So if there's a little bit of barking,
I'll just pause and then
we'll resume the video.
Occasionally you might hear some barking,
but here what I'm doing is
I'm managing expectations.
And this is a tool that you
can use to help manage stress
in whatever environments you're in,
personal or professional.
But when you manage
expectations for yourself
and for others effectively,
that helps you manage stress.
And so now I don't have to be stressed
about the dogs barking.
And if you hear the dogs barking,
you'll understand what's going on.
And then there'll just be
a little break in the video
from when they started
barking to when they stopped.
And then I'll pick up
wherever we left off.
But that's helping me avoid stress,
just managing this expectation with you.
And it's also modeling for you
one of the tools that we can use
to manage stress in our own lives
is just to manage expectations,
both with ourselves
and with others, right?
So to have that clarity of conversation
and to have clarity about what to expect
and what might occur, helps
us avoid and manage stress.
And then the last thing I wanna say
about course details here
is that there's a difference
between soft science and hard science.
And so, hard science is like
math, physics, chemistry.
It's formulas and recipes.
It's definitive, it's discreet.
It's exactly reproducible, exactly.
Like if one person does it,
another person can exactly
achieve the exact same results.
Soft science, on the other hand,
is where data is collected
and analyzed, empirical data,
and results are more difficult to predict
and it's more ambiguous.
It goes from like ambiguous environments
to really wicked problems.
And you can see a list here
if you wanna pause the video
of the characteristics of wicked problems.
But with soft sciences, you
find that what you discover
are more like principles and guidelines.
And so we are definitely going to learn
principles and guidelines in this course.
And the primary takeaway
is one of those principles
and it's a guideline that we can implement
into our own lives, but
this is soft science.
It isn't like two plus two is
always going to equal four.
It's a soft science.
So it's something that you have to take
and apply in your own life.
And you take those principles
and you take those guidelines
you apply 'em in your own
life, and then you use them
and work with them in the way
which seems to be best for you
to achieve your own best personal results.
So everybody's slightly different,
but these are the results
that are shown on aggregate
through empirical data
that when you do this,
these results are what is achieved.
But in yourself, it might take some time.
It's not just like,
okay, added two plus two,
now I've got four.
You start to apply this in your life
and it might be a little
challenging at first to apply it
and then after a while
it might become easier.
And then it could be
this incremental thing
that you realize over time
the benefits of starting
to shift and change your
narratives around stress.
And so, it's more of a soft
science than a hard science.
And I just wanna make
sure that that was clear
from the outset that this is something
that is like a skill of basketball.
Like, basketball's not math.
It's definitely more of a skill.
And this, too, is a
skill, and it's something
that with practice, you will
get better at over time.
All right, so those are a
few of the course details.
In the next video, we're gonna talk
about how as you gain new information,
that allows you to have new
opportunities in your life
to do things differently
and to live in more
effective and optimal ways.
See in the next video where we'll talk
about new information
equaling new opportunities
(gentle music)