(gentle music)
- When I was young,
I had a teacher one time
share with me this phrase
and this phrase has
stuck with me ever since
and I've reflected on it many
different times in my life.
But the phrase was this, the phrase was
ignorance is the source of all suffering.
Ignorance is the source of all suffering.
And I think this is a
really interesting phrase
because the corollary to this phrase
is that as we come out of ignorance,
we also come outta suffering.
As we gain new knowledge
and new information,
that leads to new opportunities.
And it allows us to live
in a more skillful way
where we have a more skillful life
and we can avoid suffering.
And so, I just wanna
speak to this for a moment
because as you go through this course,
you're gonna gain new knowledge,
you're gonna gain new skills,
you're gonna gain new information
and that's gonna allow
you to live your life
in a more skillful way.
And that's gonna be great
both for you individually
and also for your entire organization.
As other individuals
within your organization
become more skillful, as
you become more skillful
within an organization,
the entire organization
becomes more skillful.
So this will have, this
material in this course
will have individual and
organizational benefits.
And the amazing thing is,
is that as we each improve
ourselves individually,
collectively we improve
because a team is made up of individuals,
so as all the individuals
become more skillful,
the team becomes more skillful.
So if you optimize individuals,
you optimize groups of individuals, right?
So optimize individuals
and you optimize groups of individuals.
And so this is a really
profound opportunity
that all of us always have,
but that you are acting upon
right now to gain new
knowledge, to educate ourselves,
to learn something new,
to come out of ignorance,
to come out of suffering
and to become more skillful
so that we can operate
in the world individually
and collectively in a more skillful way
and build a more skillful life
and build more skillful organizations
and realize greater success,
individually and collectively.
So it's a wonderful
thing that you're doing
and I just want to commend you for that
and encourage you to take the time,
to invest the time, a couple of hours.
And if you invest the time in this course,
you're gonna gain some great new
pieces of knowledge and
information and skills and material
which will help you in your life
and also benefit everybody
else that you work with.
And if other individuals
go in your organization
go through this course,
it'll also help them.
So the right information
can change your life.
Here I am with a picture of
one of my former students.
He used to be a lab attendant at a college
and then he took a couple of my classes
and now he is an employee
at Apple Computers
and he was recently recognized
as one of the top 200 employees
and he got to go to a special barbecue
with the CEO, Tim Cook, and they hung out.
But if you invest in
learning and in growing,
you will change, new opportunities
will open to you in your life,
you'll be able to build
a more skillful life
because you will become more skillful.
And so that's a wonderful thing to do.
And so if you just take consistent action
in a skillful direction every
day, learn a little bit,
go through the course,
one or two videos a day,
over a couple of weeks, you're gonna learn
some amazing things
and it's gonna help you
build a more skillful life.
So never give up, just keep going.
I included a little quote here
from the Dalai Lama that I saw
one time that I really liked.
So you could pause the
video and read through that.
But just keep going.
You're doing great.
Move through all these videos.
You're gonna learn some wonderful skills
and it's gonna help you
build a more skillful life.
See you in the next video where
we will continue learning.
See you in the next video.
(gentle music)